<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docs on PRC2</title><link>https://fontysvenlo.github.io/prc2_web/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Docs on PRC2</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 11:32:04 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fontysvenlo.github.io/prc2_web/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unit Testing Basics</title><link>https://fontysvenlo.github.io/prc2_web/docs/unit-testing-basics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 11:32:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://fontysvenlo.github.io/prc2_web/docs/unit-testing-basics/</guid><description>Write your own tests! Throughout the exercises of PRC1, you have become acquainted with the value of tests: You have a way of checking if your code is any good without having to test each and every part manually. You clicked on the nice TMC button in NetBeans and then you could see which parts of your code worked, and which didn’t. There is a catch though: Out there in the real world, there won’t be any NetBeans button doing that magic for you, nor will some teacher or school provide the tests for you, so you will be on your own.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://fontysvenlo.github.io/prc2_web/docs/topics/arrangeactassert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fontysvenlo.github.io/prc2_web/docs/topics/arrangeactassert/</guid><description>Arrange Act Assert Some action. When designing tests it is good to keep the ideas of making action movies in the back of your head. Looking at some the making of…​ can be quite instructive in this case. For a scene to be taken, there is typically quite some preparation involved like hanging Spiderman on a thin cable from the ceiling, making sure the crook is in the right position so he can land or receive the first punches and so on.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://fontysvenlo.github.io/prc2_web/docs/topics/assertjexamples/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fontysvenlo.github.io/prc2_web/docs/topics/assertjexamples/</guid><description>AssertJ examples. In our course we to stick to AssertJ library where possible.
The rationale for that is:
The AssertJ assertion API is very powerful and can easily turn overly strict or brittle tests into more effective tests. You have come across tests in the mooc that insisted on specific formatting. With AssertJ you can specify elements you want to see and do not want to see.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://fontysvenlo.github.io/prc2_web/docs/topics/assumptions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fontysvenlo.github.io/prc2_web/docs/topics/assumptions/</guid><description>Assumptions There are test cases that are only useful under certain conditions:
The test is only meaningful on a specific Operating System.
The test needs a database connection and only executes when available.
A file must be present.
A &amp;#39;slow&amp;#39; test flag is set in some file, which only executes the test when that flag is set. Used to avoid slow tests in the normal write-compile-test cycle.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://fontysvenlo.github.io/prc2_web/docs/topics/parameterizedtests/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fontysvenlo.github.io/prc2_web/docs/topics/parameterizedtests/</guid><description>Parameterized tests You will often see that test methods look a lot like each other. As an example: In the fraction exercise, in most test methods you have two inputs and one or two results, then an operation is done followed by some assertion, often of the same kind. This quickly leads to the habit of copy and waste programming. Many errors are introduced this way: You copy the original, tweak the copy a bit and you are done.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://fontysvenlo.github.io/prc2_web/docs/topics/softassertions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fontysvenlo.github.io/prc2_web/docs/topics/softassertions/</guid><description>Soft Assertions Sometimes you have a pressing need to assert more than one thing in a test method, because two or more values always come in pairs and setting stuff up and dividing it over multiple methods would make the test less readable, which is bad.
However, having multiple asserts in one method is bad style, because the first problem that occurs is the only failure that will be reported by the test.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://fontysvenlo.github.io/prc2_web/docs/topics/tdd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fontysvenlo.github.io/prc2_web/docs/topics/tdd/</guid><description>What are tests and why do we need them? The way that you have worked with Java so far is that you had to write some code to implement something. For example you had to implement a bird watcher system or a telephone book, in which you could save people with their telephone numbers and look them up, too. You probably created classes called PhoneBook or BookEntry, and you had variables such as String personName, int phoneNumber and maybe a List or a Map which contained all the people and their phone numbers.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://fontysvenlo.github.io/prc2_web/docs/topics/testrecipes1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fontysvenlo.github.io/prc2_web/docs/topics/testrecipes1/</guid><description>Test Recipe I, Test Equals and hashCode We may sprinkle our testing stuff with a few recipes for often occurring tests. This is the the first installment.
Equals and hashCode are not twins in the direct sense, but indeed methods whose implementation should have a very direct connection. From the java Object API follows that:
Two objects that are equal by their equal method, than their hashCode should also be equal.</description></item></channel></rss>